<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meo Electric</title>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.meoelectric.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://blog.meoelectric.com/</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 14:38:05 -0400</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 EV Announcements from EVS29</title>
        <link>http://blog.meoelectric.com/evs29/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.meoelectric.com/evs29/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The 29th Electric Vehicle Symposium (EVS), the world’s largest international electric vehicle conference, was held in Montréal from June 19-22. It saw global technological, academic, and government leaders come together to discuss market and policy topics and showcased the latest innovations and technologies in vehicle electrification. Here’s are just a few of the week’s highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fast-charging-in-quebec&quot;&gt;Fast-charging in Quebec&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Québec’s Premier Philippe Couillard reinforced the government’s dedication to electrify the province by announcing government plans to install 6 EV fast-charging stations along Highway 20 between Montreal and Québec that would be completed within the next 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the government of Québec already provides rebates for those buying electric vehicles or installing charging stations in their homes, the implementation of additional charging stations along the highway provides even greater incentive for those who are thinking of purchasing an EV. Increased availability of charging stations will continue to reduce Quebecers’ range anxiety, an issue that many EV owners have to worry about when making long-distance trips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/evs29/image01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tesla charging&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flo-network-and-a-smart-home-charger&quot;&gt;FLO Network and a smart home charger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AddÉnergie unveiled their FLO Network (a reimagining of the VER Network) and released an EV home charging station designed to withstand the Canadian winter. It will be available in Fall 2016 for around $1,195 and is eligible for the government’s charging station rebates for purchasing and installation of the station. FLO Home™ is entirely made in Québec, perfect for those who enjoy supporting the local Canadian economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/evs29/image05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FLO home charger&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;telematics-for-partial-electric-fleets&quot;&gt;Telematics for partial-electric fleets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FleetCarma, a connected platform for electric vehicle owners, debuted a cutting-edge telematics device for fleets wishing to increase their total number of EVs in operation. Dubbed “C2,” the device is the first of its kind that is able to support diesel, hybrid, gasoline and electric vehicles. Data from C2 can indicate which vehicles in the fleet are best to be replaced with EVs while connecting these new electric vehicles into the same telematics system as the rest of the fleet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/evs29/image00.png&quot; alt=&quot;Parked fleet of cars&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bmw-battery-storage&quot;&gt;BMW battery storage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BMW introduced a new home energy storage system that can be operated by either new or old BMW i3 batteries. It can be integrated with both solar panels and charging stations, extending battery life beyond vehicle usage for ultimate sustainability. This presents an alternative solution to simply recycling or throwing out your old car battery; It could be hanging on your wall providing power instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/evs29/image06.png&quot; alt=&quot;BMW i3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-bigger-leaf-battery&quot;&gt;A bigger Leaf battery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kazuo Yajima, the global director of electric vehicles and hybrid-electric vehicle engineering for Nissan, confirmed that the next-generation Nissan Leaf will have a larger battery pack with a 60-kWh capacity. This would allow the car to have a range around 200 miles in comparison to 107 miles with the current model’s 30-kWh battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/evs29/image04.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nissan Leaf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wireless-motors&quot;&gt;Wireless motors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a panel presentation, graduate student Takehiro Imura of the University of Tokyo presented his work on a wireless in-wheel motor. The motors use magnetic coils to transmit power through air as opposed to cables and can circulate power across 20cm, transmitting power with around 95% efficiency, according to his research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/evs29/image03.png&quot; alt=&quot;In-wheel wireless motor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wireless-charging-with-halo&quot;&gt;Wireless charging with Halo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also showcased at the symposium was Qualcomm’s wireless EV charging system, powered by magnetics. With a base pad, vehicle pad and controller unit, Qualcomm’s charging system, named, “Halo,” has four different power options from 3.4kW to 22kW. A pad is installed underneath the vehicle so that it lines up with the base pad when parked overtop for the most effective charge; An app that comes with the system assists the driver in determining the optimal positioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/evs29/image02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BMW on a wireless charger&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Perks of Driving an EV in Québec</title>
        <link>http://blog.meoelectric.com/quebec-benefits/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.meoelectric.com/quebec-benefits/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Québec government openly pushes for an increase of electric vehicles on the road and provides many incentives for the population to help them in reaching their goal of 100 000 EVs by 2020. Not only are carpool lanes open to those driving EVs on the highway, but those driving EVs are also exempt from paying tolls on the road. As of March 2016, 9211 electric vehicles have been registered in Québec which makes it the province with the most EVs in Canada. Ontario comes in behind with 6506 and British Columbia next with 3682 registered EVs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to purchase or lease a “green car” in Québec anytime soon, you will be eligible for a rebate from the government. While the largest rebate stands at $8000, it only applies to vehicles that are all-electric and plug-in hybrids with a big enough battery capacity. If electric motorcycles are more your style, the government is offering a $2000 rebate, though it has to be completely powered by electricity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/qcbenefits/image03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quebec keeps you recharged, too. The government is offering a rebate of up to $600 for the purchase and installation of a new 240V EV charging station in your home. Businesses and organisations are also eligible for financial assistance if they wish to install charging stations for their employees as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, individuals and businesses looking to purchase and install a charger can take advantage of Meo Electric’s turnkey service. Rather than having to work separately with the supplier and an electrician, customers in Montreal and Ottawa/Gatineau receive an all-in-one solution, including charger purchase, installation, aid with incentive programs, and ongoing monitoring and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/qcbenefits/image01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking of purchasing a Tesla? The city of Montréal is more than accommodating for owners of this EV. Montréal’s Tesla service and sales centre is the largest in North America, and Québec boasts 3 Tesla supercharger locations, one located in Montréal with 2 chargers, one in Magog with 8 chargers, and one in Drummondville with 8 chargers. Plus, a new 12-stall supercharger station at Montréal’s Place Vertu is already under construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/qcbenefits/image02.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tesla supercharger&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With government incentives and a wide availability of charging stations, Québec is an ideal province for electric vehicle owners, allowing the province to continue leading the charge of transport electrification in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
